Guide to the Women's Advancement Initiative records ARCH079
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Women's Advancement Initiative records
2006-2011
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford. Women's Advancement Initiative
ARCH079
2.92 Linear Feet (7 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Historical Note
When Hartford College for Women phased out its undergraduate program, its funds were transferred to a new entity, eventually called "The Women's Education and Leadership Fund, a Legacy of Hartford College for Women." Jennifer Sanborn became the first director in 2005. She was later joined by a second staff member Donna Haighitah. Jennifer Sanborn left the University to assume a position at Mount Holyoke in 2011.
The WELFund changed its name in the fall of 2015 to the Women's Advancement Initiative.
Scope and Contents
The majority of the collection pertains to the programs offered or funded by the Women's Advancement Initiative.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by accession.
Women -- Education (Higher) -- United States; University of Hartford. Women's Advancement Initiative; University of Hartford. Women's Education and Leadership Fund
- Acc. 2011.22 (WELFund records), 1991-2012; Bulk 2006-2011; 2.92 Linear Feet (7 containers)
  Custodial History
  This first components of this collection came to the archives from the Welfund office in 2011. Additional material was added afterwards.
  Arrangement
  The accession is arranged into three series:
  Projects
  Directors, Board, and Administrators
  Events, Programs, and Annual Reports
  - Directors, Board, and Administrators, 2007-2011
    - Deliberations, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Not At This Time, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Grants, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Work Groups; Grants Strengthening, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Board Meetings, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Events & Membership, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Financial Records, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Grantees Surveys, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Conferences with EWS, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Jaffe-Barzach, Amy, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Projects, 1991-2011; Bulk 2006-2011
    The Projects series is arranged in chronological order by the year in which the project started, and then arranged alphabetically by the grant recipient's last name.
    - Aliotta, Jilda/ Judge Barron & her Social Clinic, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Aust. Kandyce/ The Alumnae Council for Women, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Lindsay, Delois/ Student Leadership & Career Development Conference, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
    - Mair, Margaret/ Sophie Tucker: A Woman for Our Times, exhibit at Jewish Historical Society of Hart., 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Segal/ Energy-Technology Camp for Young Women, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Tears/Teens Experiencing Abusive Relationships, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Applications, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Barrett, Karen & Sullivan, Karen/ Scholarships for Adult Students, 2006-2010 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Barstow/ Title IX, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Blanchard. Yvette/ The Effectiveness of Newborn Behavioral Observation System, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Buckberrough, Sherry/ Visiting Artist, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Cahilland McCloud/ Her Stories, 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Coleman, Susan/ Financial Literacy in Female Undergrads, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Lauren/ Feminisms: Film, Video, Politics, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cook, Lauren/ Object: Journal of Feminist Experimental Media, 2007-2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Dix/ College for Low Income Mothers of Young Children, 1991; 1992; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fang, Clara/ Sweet Day/ Society of Women Engineers, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Firkatian/ Diplomats and Dreamers, 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Galvin, Arnold & Cooley/ Empoering UofH Frontline Staff, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Galvin, Lynn; Arnold, Marge; Cooley, Elaine/ Empowering Frontline, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
    - Griswold, Renwick/ University of Hartford and Harriet Beecher Stowe Center/ Women's Living History Project, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Griswold; UHarriet and Another Video, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hu, Duffy, Gurt/ Attending Flanerty Seminar in Media and Film at Colgate University, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Kane and McKenna- Grant/ RAD Systems Programming, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Koffman/ Contemporary Music for Saxaphone Composed by Women, 2007-2011 (Box 3, Folder 9, Box Shared CD Box 3)
      Scope and Contents
      This includes a copy of the CD Carillon Sky, which was a result of this project.
    - La Due, Pines/ Engineers without Borders, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Mahan, Eric/ Women in Science at Hartford (WISH), 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Miceli, Melinda and Misovich, Stephen/ Promoting Women's Educational Engagement through College Course Discussion Boards, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Pence, Laura/ A National Capstone Womwen in Science Experience (WISE), 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Rudman, Carl, Seaton/ Women Composer Festival, 2007-2009 (Box 3, Folder 14, Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Shackett/ Kotran, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Women Building Cultures of Peace, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Applications, 2008-2014 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
    - Benson, Melanie/ A Beautiful Nothing, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Borucinska, Joanna/ Morphological Boindicators... in Sharks, 2006-2009 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Campbell, Elizabeth/ Society of Women Engineers, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Fang, Clara/ Transportation Systems, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Fearn, Kaeza/ 9th Annual Women Composers Festival, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jones, Elital/ The Gail Champlin Annual Speakers Program, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Klicka, Ann; Knauf, Jennifer/ The Flaberty Films Festival, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - La Due, Rachel & Pines, David, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Levesque/ Analysis of DWA Checkpoints, 2007-2009 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Lindsay/ Girls Scouts U of UHA!, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 5-7)
    - Marques, Maria/ Women's Health Forums, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Matacin, Maia/ Women for Change, 2008-2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - McKenna- Grant/ Alumnae Women Lunch Series, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - McKenna-Grant/ Dating Violence Curriculum (TEAR), 2008 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Owens, Katherine/ Mentoring Student Research, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Poggio, Natacha/ Water for India Campaign, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Dankin Women's Triatholon as Feminist Performance, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Aust, Kandyce/ Alumnae Council for Women, 2008; 2009 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Aust, Kandyce/ Women Alumnae Event, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Bravos, Alexis & THSGH/ Women in WWII Film, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Christensen, Mary/ Bloomfield Girls Leadership Academy, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Fang/ Hardware in the Loop Testing...Automobile Traffic, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Grantham/ Leading Forward Leadership Program, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Llumoka/ After School Science & Engineering for Girls, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Jones, Eleta/ Marketing Internships for Students, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mardinley/ Nine Artiettas by Barbara Strozzi transcribed, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Milanovic, Ivana & Eppes, Tom/ Leading Chnage in Engineering Departments, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Pasquerall, Lynn/ Advance Grant, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Pogursky/ Art Residency at Vermont Studio Center, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Vigeant, Michelle/ Advancement of Women in Acoustical Engineering, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Weinholz, Don/ Jocelyn Bell Burnell University of Hartford Visiting Scientist, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Yu/ Promoting Interest in STEM Subjects with Educational Video, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Aust/ Homecoming for Women, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Brown, Nadia/ Attend Symposium on Critical Race Studies, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Gort/ Off Cycle Grant Request/ Media Artist Janet Biggs, 2010-2011 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Lankford/ Get Set/ Science Day Camp for Girls, 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Symmonds & Campbell/ Society of Women Engineers/ Sweet Day MacDonald, 2007-2010 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Events, Program, and Annual Reports, 2008-2012
    - Annual Report, 2011-2012 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Brochures, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - CT Secretary of State, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Donor Reports, 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Events/ A Celebration of Aspiring and Inspiring Women, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Laura Johnson Initiative for Women Leaders, 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
    - Women's Wednesday, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Acc. 2015-10-27-01, Circa 2006 - 2015
  - Brochures, Circa 2006 - circa 2015 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Donor Report 2010-2011, Circa 2011 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Women Composers in Music Theatre, 2015 Sep 27 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Women's Advancement Initiative Microfiber Cloth and Cards, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Acc. 2016-09-27-01, HCW Class of 1964 - 50th reunion, Circa 2014 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Consists of photographs of a 50th class reunion [Class of 1964?], and older photographs identified by the members of that reunion.